## **Software Engineer**

# **HWEE SHAN WONG**

+44 7424 586 826

HweeWong

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Natwest Group, Edinburgh **Software Engineer, Enterprise Engineering |** since April 2018

[ { "item": "• Automated the process of onboarding users to developer tools and technologies which reduced lead time from 48 hours to 5 mins." }, { "item": "• Delivered Spring Boot Java microservices in event-driven architecture and have deep understanding of the system design." }, { "item": "• Actively involved in decision making of system design and architecture improvements by collaborating closely with customers/SMEs." }, { "item": "• Cultivated behaviour-driven and test-driven development within the team which enhanced system reliability and team's DevOps metrics. Software development cycle time KPI reduced by 50%." }, { "item": " • Presented proof of concepts for various authentication/authorisation modules for tools which drove infrastructure and tooling improvements." }, { "item": "• Mentored junior engineers and continuously building best practices within the team such as codifying workflow using plantUML." } ]

#### Natwest Group, Edinburgh

**Technology Service Analyst** | Sep 2017 – Apr 2018

[ { "item": "• Responsible for migrating server data from bespoke tools to standardised ServiceNow Configuration Management Database for better consolidation of enterprise data." }, { "item": "• Automated data gathering and validation process for the migration work to ensure data quality was high and consistent." }, { "item": "• Drove the implementation of agile ways of working in my team through creation of manageable goals and Sprint boards." } ]

#### Merck, Sharp & Dohme (MSD), Newcastle

Chemical Engineer | Aug 2015 – Sep 2016

[ { "item": "• Supported technical operations in solid-dose tablet production facility and operated within GMP standards." }, { "item": "• Solved process deviations and problems by identifying root causes using Lean Six Sigma methodologies." } ]

## **EDUCATION**

#### First Class Honors

MEng Chemical Engineering with Industrial Experience, University **of Manchester |** Sep 2013 – Jun 2017

4A\* in Chemistry, Biology, Physics, Mathematics A Levels, Taylor's College | Jan 2012 - Jun 2013

### **About me**

Hi, my name is Hwee and currently a software engineer in Natwest Group. I am passionate about developing tools and products to boost engineering experience. I have experience in delivering microservices using the twelve-factor app methodology, designing event-driven architecture and implementing infrastructure solutions and services.